快点换衣服  就快开席啦!
Would you hurry up? The banquet is about to begin
人家是六时恭候
everybody's gonna be there at six
换衣服
Change!
妈咪，我不去喝喜酒可不可以
Mommy, do I have to go?
可以
Of course!
每次我都有去
But I went every time
不可以  所以这次也不例外
that's why this can't be an exception
招弟，换衣服
Jody, go change!
如果你不第一时间去换衣服
If you don't go change at this very minute,
今晚你不要去喝喜酒
you don't have to go to this banquet tonight.
谢谢老爸
Thank you, dad!
然后由明天起，没得上学
And you don't go to school starting from tomorrow
谢谢老爸
thank you, dad!
以后不用再认我是你老爸了
And don't call me dad anymore
谢谢老爸
thank you, dad!
因为我不再是你老爸了
And since I'm no longer your dad,
所以就没钱给你做模型了
I don't have to buy you those models
我回房间换衣服了，老爸
I'll go change now, dad!
-老婆，我的西装烫好没有   -我漂不漂亮？
Honey, is my suit ready yet?
-挂在房间了，那么紧张  -漂亮
It's hanging in the bedroom. Take it easy, will you?
当然紧张啦
How can 1?
所谓人要衣装，佛要金装
Even a Buddha needs his gold robe
香港地先敬罗衣后敬人
in Hong Kong, people respect you for what you wear
人的价值是从穿衣服看出来的
you can tell the wealth of a guy from his clothes
不用说别的
for instance...
香港的国货公司
Toe local emporiums here in Hong Kong
永远输给日本百货公司
are always behind the Japanese department stores
就是输在一张包装纸
why? Packaging!
香港这地方就是那么残酷的
Hong Kong is a mean city, I tell you
-把梳还给我
give me back my comb
-不给，梳是我的
no way. The comb is mine
还给我！
give it back!
打仗呀！
What is this? A war!
这种房子是房屋署叫人建的
This building is built by the housing department
很脆的
it's extremely fragile!
她拿了我的梳
She took my comb
招弟，出来！
Jody, come out!
这把梳是她送给我的
She gave me the comb as a present
她从来都不用，我就拿回它
but she never used it, so I took it back
那你就不对了
then you're wrong
既然你把梳送了给她
since you gave her the comb
用不用是她的自由
it's up to her whether she wants to use it
-如果你要用，就要问她
if you want to use it, ask her if you can borrow it
-妈咪啊
mommy!
问她借
Go ask her!
小妞，借把梳来用
Can I borrow your comb?
不行！
No!
妹妹，请你把梳借给我
Sis, would you please lend me your comb?
你拿去吧！
Take it!
经过这件事你学到了什么？
So what did you learn from this?
我学到以后都不送东西给别人
I learned not to give present to anyone
穿得那么漂亮干嘛？
why are you so dressed up?
那些姨妈、姑姐又不会欣赏的
Those elderly aunts and uncles won't appreciate it
我没打算去喝喜酒
I don't intent go to the banquet
待会有男朋友来接我
my boyfriend is going to pick me up later
可不可以接我一起去
can I go too?
好啦
OK
老婆！这条领带那么皱
Honey, why is this tie so wrinkled?
替我烫一烫行不行？
Could you iron it for me?
烫一烫行不行？
Are your clothes wrinkled?
不皱！没有皱！
No, they're ok!
骥叔，骤婶！
Uncle bill! Auntie Lydia!
穿得那么漂亮，去街吗？
All dressed up, so pretty! Going out?
废话！
Idiot!
去喝喜酒！
Yeah, we're going to a banquet!
如果是我请客
If I were going to throw a feast,
我一定请你们全家
I'd invite your whole family,
在这儿屋邨的上上下下
everybody who lives in this housing estate
骥叔这家人是最体面的
knows that uncle bill's family is always the sharpest!
你们看他们的三位千金
Just look, their three daughters
打扮得多漂亮，像公王一样
are just like princesses!
照我说，生女更划算
I say, it's better to have daughters than sons!
好像骤叔没有儿子  全部是女儿
Uncle bill only has daughters
他自己在电视台是报告新闻的
he's a news anchorman in a TV station,
这次一定近水楼台先得月
so he's at an advantage, really
为什么呀？南姑
how's that, auntie nam?
提名他女儿去选美
He'll nominate his daughters for beauty pageants
大女选香港小姐
the eldest daughter will be miss Hong Kong
二女选亚洲小姐
the second daughter miss Asia
老土
how boring!
-骠婶可以选健美小姐  -是呀...
And auntie Lydia can be miss aerobic
她的身材那么棒
you know... her figure...
说什么那么好笑？
What's so funny?
在说骤叔的女儿做小姐
We were saying uncle bill's daughters can be miss...
舞小姐？
Miss hooker?
招弟还可以选电视小姐
Jody can be miss television
招弟还那么小
but Jody is still a child
等她长大了，可能不流行这种玩意了
pageants won't be popular when she grows up
怎么会没有？
why not?
特区小姐！
How about miss special area?
说得来也差不多
Well, actually it's not that far away
是不是呀，骠叔
isn't that right, uncle bill?
你口痒呀，去吃无比膏吧
You got a big mouth. Go swallow some k-y!
老公，你去拉她出来
Darling, you'd better go get her
招弟，快点啦！
Jody, hurry up!
记住，到了酒楼别叫那么多汽水喝
Remember, don't drink too many coke in the restaurant
不然给人家说我没钱买汽水给你喝
or people will think we can't afford it
来弟呀，走过来屋檐下
lolita, come walk over here
楼下会掉下东西来
somebody might throw something down, you know
不会那么巧
it won't happen!
快点啦，这儿安全一点
It's safer here
笑口枣
Smiley Joe!
美亚
Mia!
Ma ma Mia!
我老爸
My daddy!
换衫  他是谁？
Shut up! Who's he?
-我不去喝喜酒
we are going to a concert
拜拜  -那我呢？
I'm not going to the banquet, bye!
我做了五百块人情呀
But I paid 500 bucks for the gift certificate!
你带些回来给我吃
Bring me some oranges then
这就叫做“女大不中留”
look at her attitude
叫你别生女的
I told you not to give birth to any daughters
这两个不是我生的  不要算在我头上
I didn't conceive them. Don't put them into my access
这个呢？
what about tier?
老爸，你们去哪里喝？
Daddy, which way are you going?
-去铜锣湾   -是呀
Causeway bay!
糟糕！不顺路
Not in the same direction. Too bad!
-拜拜        -拜拜
Bye
计程车
Taxi!
发财啦？
Have you struck a gold mine?
坐地铁
Take the subway
坐地铁？
subway?
地铁又快又舒服  还有冷气叹
Subway is fast and safe, and air-conditioned as well
-走吧     -走吧！去叹吧！来
come!
前往中环及港岛线的乘客
Passengers boarding the island line to central,
请到二号月台上车
please go to platform no. 2!
那么多人
So crowded!
碰巧下班嘛
It's the rush hour!
上不到车的乘客  请乘下一趟列车
Passenger who couldn't get on, please take next train
来弟，这儿有位子
Lolita, there's a seat here
快点，不然给别人坐了
hurry, or somebody will take it
你坐吧
you sit, mom!
我坐啦
Okay!
真是老土
How boring
你看！靓女
you look!
下一站是尖沙咀
Next stop, tsimshatsui
站不稳了
Oops!
非礼呀
Help!
-缺德鬼，非礼人那么大胆   -打死你...
You creep. Trying to molest my daughter?
不知道是读
What school do you go to?
哪一间学校的
what a weirdo!
两位王婚人请坐中间
Two parents sitting in the middle
笑一笑
smile
来弟，坐下
Lolita, sit down!
别管她
Leave her alone!
九姑婆，大姨妈  -一起来拍照    -去照相了
Ninth auntie, big auntie come take a picture...
照好了，请各位回座位
Okay! Please sit!
司机张，花王炳 -我们也有份喔   -是啊
Driver Chang, gardener bing, you two as well,
走吧，轮不到我们的了
Let's go, we can never make it
-我们去找位子坐下    -好的
let's find some place to sit
来弟
lolita!
还有哪一家没拍照的
Who else hasn't taken pictures?
有呀...漏掉了...
Yeah... we missed someone...!
漏了LUCKY和DOLLY
We missed lucky and Dolly!
两只小狗很好玩
These two dogs are cute!
各位请随便
Everybody please!
干杯
Cheers
谢谢
Thank you
这样够了
That's enough!
PAUL，你的法拉利三零八
Your car...?
-这样就够了...   -香港的路怎么飞得起来呢
That's enough!
开游艇就好玩了
Okay!
说起来  我那间房子就快入伙了
I am going to move into my new house
到时候我开个酒会
I'll throw a housewarming party and invite you all
请你们来庆祝
how much did you spend on decorating the house?
才两百多万
Only 2 million plus
是呀...才两百多万
yes... only 2 million or so!
住是好住，就是远了一点
It's a nice house, but it's far
说方便嘛  还是表哥你们那儿好
I bet you place is more convenient
-你们还是住在市区的公共房屋吗？  -是吗？
are you still living in a housing estate?
-是啊    -是啊
Right!
改天我们出来去拜候你们
We'll pay you a visit some other time
不用客气了
no need to bother!
最近我们也在装修
We are just renovating
是啊
right!
来弟，你今年读中学几年级？
Lolita, what grade are you in?
读几年级？
What grade?
在读预科
Form six
就快考大学了
she's going to college soon
为什么不送她去外国读书？
why not send her abroad?
-我女儿连“淘汰试”也不让她考
- I didn't even let my daughter - 1 go to the bathroom
-我去洗手间
sit through those exam
-就送她去罗省读书  -我呢？
- and send her to school in la - Leave me~
明年考罗省大学了
and she's going to ucla next year
就快一九九七了
it will soon be 1997
有没有打算移民？
are you planning to immigrate?
我们不打算移民
We have no such thoughts
我们虽然是香港人
we are Hong kongese
体内流的是中国人的血液
we have Chinese blood, you know
应该投向祖国的休抱
and should stay with our own kind
移民，是不负责任的行为
immigrating is irresponsible
我们应该以不屈不挠的香港精神
we should live up to the invincible Hong Kong image
留在这儿  做大时代转变的见证人
and stay here... witness the change of times
为实现祖国四个现代化尽一分力
we should work towards the modernization of our country
所以我在这儿呼吁大家
so I urge you all to
留在香港
stay in Hong Kong
不要做人家的三等公民
don't be a third class citizen elsewhere
还有一碗谁要？
Who wants this bowl?
给我表哥，他不常吃
Give it to my cousin, he doesn't always eat
经理在不在
I want to see the manager
你不能进去
you can't go in!
不吃，酸的
No, it's sour!
经理，我是来告诉你
Manager, I've come to tell you
我替你买了六合彩
I bought the Mark six for you
好的
OK
-我先出去，经理  -好的
I'll see you later, manager!
那些号码我对过了，没有错
I've checked the numbers
还有你的车匙
and your car key...
坐下
Uncle bill, sit down!
你刚才没看到什么吧
You didn't see anything just then, did you?
什么都没看到
No, I saw nothing
看过上次试片室
compared to what I saw the screening room last time
这次是小儿科啦
this is only chicken shit!
还有在停车场那次
And that time at the car park...
骠叔，你报告新闻都十几年了
Uncle bill, you've be anchor for more than 10 years
你应该知道什么是应该说
you should know what to say
什么是不应该说的
and what should not to say please
谢谢
no, thanks
我一直都是照住公司的稿说
just any what's in the manuscript
我不会乱说的
not a word more!
那最好了
That's good!
下个礼拜有白金巨星之夜  你看不看？
There's a superstar concert next week wanna go?
我不是很喜欢看
Not very interested!
应该看的，你就要去看
You should see what you ought to see,
不应该看的，就当没看过
and not see what you ought not to see
是不是？
is that right?
是，多谢经理
Yes, thank you, manager!
新闻部，我是骠叔
News department, I'm uncle bill!
骠叔，监制有请呀
The producer wants to see you
女魔头？
that witch?
监制
Producer
找我？有什么事
what does she want from me?
骠叔，你在新闻邵做了十八年
Uncle bill, you've been with us for 18 years
没有功也有劳
you'd put in sweat and tears
按照公司的政策  我一定要通知你
according to company policy I must notify you...
终干轮到我升职啦
Of ray promotion?
三个月试用期，由今天开始
Your three month trial period starts today
什么，我在这里做了十八年
what? But I've been here for 18 years!
都还是试用期
Why do I need a trial period?
我入行的时候  你还在念中学
You were still in school when I started my job
我们不要说这些
let's not talk about these things
就说你上个月
just talk about last month
你闯过多少次祸？  出错了几多次？
how many mistakes did you make in reading the news
-一次，两次...
once, twice...!
-你不用数了
Stop counting!
我已经把你犯错的镜头全邵剪辑好
We've edited your bloopers together!
你睁大眼睛看清楚
Now watch!
最近当局搞了个工业安全运动
In order to promote industrial safety
加强教育地盘工人
we need to pump more education into construction work
在有危险警告的地万  不要乱走
don't go near places with danger signs...
那是意外
That's an accident
接住这次该不是意外吧
this now shouldn't be an accident!
我在沙头角报告台风消息
I am covering the typhoon situation in sha-tau kok
这儿多处水浸  山泥倾泻
there's flooding in several places, and landslides...
好大风呀
It's really windy!
我已经知道发生什么事
No, I already know what happened!
这条车匙是经理的  请你替我交还给他
Please return this car key to the manager for me
因为你跟他的关系密切一点
because you are close to him
冬菇部
The mushroom department!
什么，冬菇部？
What mushroom department?
是呀，这儿是
This place specializes in mushrooms
专炖人冬菇的
the two concert tickets I just mentioned
我叫秘书送下来给你
will be sent down to you
不用客气了，经理
don't bother! Manager,
你留住自己看吧
you can keep them for yourself!
什么事？
What happened?
你去问我们的监制就知道了
You just ask my producer!
我现在什么都看透了
Now I see everything!
总之人穷就恶
Now I know why poor son always get mean
真是离谱
I don't believe it!
骠叔，你说
You tell me, uncle bill
我在美国读到传理系硕士
I got my master in communication in the states
回来这里做了十八个月
and have been working here for 18 months
我还要试用期
and I still need to go through a trial period
有什么好奇怪
what's so strange about it?
有人在新闻部做了十八年
Someone who has been with the news department
现在还是试用期
for 18 years, still has to go through a trial period
是谁那么窝囊
who can be that stupid?
我是他呀
I would kill myself if I were him!
我就去死了算了
Really I would rather die!
不死也没用啦
Die! Die! Die!
骠叔，刚才经理打电话来
Uncle bill, toe manager just called
他叫你把那封信还给我
he told you to return that letter to me
不好了  我也不想干了
no, I don't think I want to continue
我想退休
I want to retire
我再给你一次机会
I'll give you one more change
这儿有很多年青人在等机会
lots of young men here are waiting for their chance
不用一下子给两次机会我呀
don't waste two chances on me at the same tune!
我教你，想辞我就要紧守原则
I've to stick to your principles if you want to fire me
原则也可以变的
principles are flexible, you know
会变的就不是原则
not if they are really principles
炒得的就不是骠叔啦
not if it's uncle bill who's getting fired
屋邨生活纪要
life in the housing estate:
-眼见四大八婆在打麻将  -不要拍
Four witches are playing mah-jong
不肯上镜的是东姑  南姑之后有西姑
there are witches east, south and west
北姑不见  只剩下一粒大草菇
and gone is the wicked witch of the north...
这一铺是鸡糊啦
This is chicken feed!
不要说出来嘛
Don't say it out loud!
好，我看看我老妈的
Okay, I'll look at mom's
好棒呀
that's good!
-不要影了  -算了
- Oh! - Don't shoot!
真是的
I'll be damned!
妈  看过我的录影带
Mom, watch out for my video recorder
-不要啦  -我是香港电影新浪潮的希望
I am the hope of Hong Kong's new wave cinema
我要做史提芬史匹堡
I am Stephen spielbug!
屎忽宝？
See fut Bo?
你以为你屎忽有宝
There ain't no treasure in your asshole! Asshole!
不知道怎么会生了这个废物
I didn't know why I gave birth to this piece of trash
丁V仔呀，请你替我们换壶热茶
TV kid, would you please get me a hot tea?
服侍女人，没有尊严
It's degrading to wait on women
真是废物
you are trash!
废物也可以利用的
Trash can be made good use of
你打得怎么样？
so how did it go?
真打不惯
It's...
你真的不打啦
are you really quitting?
没有空
I haven't got time
我老公约了我去看房子
my husband and I am going to see a new house
你们知道的，我女儿都大了
you know, all my daughters are grown
地万不够住
my place is just not big enough
骠叔真有本事呀
uncle bill is such a smart guy!
六合彩可以买二十几注了
I can buy more than 20 Mark sixes with that money
老婆...你不要走...
don't go honey, don't go!
不要拉住我
Leave me alone
我答应你
I promise you: I'll go look for a job tomorrow
犯规，罚十二码
you lose, penalty!
怎么搞的，这样也罚十二码
How come? Penalty for that!
糟了，没带锁匙
Shit, forgot to bring my keys
老婆...不要走呀
honey... please don't go!
我没带锁匙怎么进去
I didn't bring me key. How can I get in!
去社会福利处吧
Go to the social welfare department
他们最拿手是破门进屋
they are good at breaking in
可以吗？
really?
你说你是郭亚女的爸爸不就行了
Tell them you are kwok ah-lui's father
对
right!
招弟，你想怎么样？
Jody, what are you doing?
切这儿！...
slice it here!
拿回来呀
Give it back!
借对丝袜给我
Can I borrow a pair of silk stockings?
你自己也有丝袜嘛
You've got your own
每对丝袜我都穿过  人家都见过了
but I've worn all mine. Everybody has seen them
你反转来穿就不行了？
turn them inside out and wear them
-来吧，借给我  -什么事？
- come on, lend me yours! - What is it?
我今晚有个跳舞比赛
I'm going to a dance contest tonight
她连丝袜也不肯借给我
and she won't even lend me her stockings
什么事？...
what is it?
割伤了一点
It's very minor, I'll get some band-aids
借个手袋给我，衬色
Lend me your purse!
为什么你老是看中我的东西
Why do you always eye my stuff?
你买回来都不用的
You never use them anyway
因为你老是借了去用
because you always borrow them
不要吵
stop it!
我的梳子全是你的头屑
Your dandruff is all over my comb
头皮屑是你自己的
that's your own dandruff
我的头没有头皮屑的
I never had dandruff!
不要吵
Stop it girls. This is a small flat
我警告你们
I am warning you!
在这间屋子里
Whoever shouts in this house
如果谁再大声说话  我就对他不客气
will be punished
老婆
honey!
老婆，我回来啦
Honey, I'm back!
你想怎么样？
What is it with you?
回来就回来好了  干嘛那么大声？
So you're back. You don't have to shout!
-老婆，潮流兴大声呀！  -走呀...
Honey, get with it!
这是城市人的节奏  年青人的时尚
The tempo of the city the fashion of the young...
不知道你在说什么
What on earth are you talking about?
我说，我们要追上潮流
I say, I want to catch up with the times
呀，对了
right!
老公，今天有封信是你的
Darling, there's a registered letter for you!
你弟弟阿尊  从马尼拉寄回来的
Your brother John from Manila
阿尊那个臭小子  他的信我从来不看
I never read his letters
起码也要看一次吧
but you got to read them at least once!
我最讨厌这个弟弟
I really dislike this brother of mine
他目无尊长
he never respected me!
你今晚去跳舞比赛吗？
are you going to the dance contest?
不用等你吃饭了
You're not coming back for dinner then
喝鲜奶
have some fresh milk!
说话哪用那么大声？
You don't have to shout!
是呀，这屋子有多大？
Yeah, this flat is so small
伟大，大功告成
great. Finally finished!
老二，给点意见
Sis, what do you think?
你就拿这个去参加模型比赛？
Are you going to the science project contest with this?
是呀，太阳系  有齐九大行星
Yeah, the solar system. The nine planets
你看怎么样？
so what do you think?
不错  才不错呀
- Not bad! - Of course!
怎么这个木星那么小的？
How come the Jupiter is so small?
地球旁边又没有月球
And there's no moon beside the earth
别故意挑剔
don't pick on it
我不知道了
I don't know
那么快就做好啦？
it is finished already?
这些球又圆
These balls are so round and so colorful
颜色又鲜艳
and they can rotate!
还会转呀  威水威水，天才儿童
You are a genius, a whiz kid
有我的血统
you definitely have my blood!
选一个六合彩号码
Pick a Mark six number
预祝我的模型得第一
well, gonna win. So number "1"
你们每人选一个号码
You each pick a number!
你自己赌好了
Yourself are a gambler
连女儿也教赌？
but why make your daughters gamblers?
选号码而已
Just asking them to pick a number!
老是想发横财  发了达也不光荣
You're always dreaming of a fortune from the sky
周润发会发财
sly stallons is a billionaire
也是全靠他自己努力
because he is hard-working
开饭啦
go serve dinner!
妈妈咪呀
Mommy!
干什么“摄铁仔”？想进来？
What do you want? Do you want to come in?
是啊...你真是聪明
Mommy, you're really smart!
妈妈咪呀
Call me aunt!
叫我伯母
Call me smiley Joe!
-叫我笑口枣  -笑口枣
Smiley Joe!
等我一会，我换件衣服
Wait for me one second, I'm going to change
慢慢来，跳舞比赛还有两个小时
don't rush, there's 2 hours before the dance contest
你会跳舞呀？
you're going to dance?
今晚我跟你姐姐是拍挡
I'm your sister's partner tonight
一定得冠军的
we going to get first place for sure
待会跳来看看
dance, let's see!
你的头发染成这样
You think your blenched hair looks pretty good?
很有型吗？
Aunt, you're wrong!
其它的才是染的
The other's...
你掉了一只耳环
are you missing an earring?
伯母，你土得好紧要
Aunt, you're really out of fashion
潮流兴戴一只耳环
you're supposed to only wear one earring these day!
你穿了耳窿呀？
You pierced your ear?
是啊，追得上潮流的青年
It's for the young, like me
二十五岁以下  全部都穿上耳窿
under 25, everyone has pierced ears
那到二十六岁  你会不会填好这个窿
after 26 years old, will you fill in the hole?
伯母，你真是会说笑
Aunt, you're a great kidder
爸爸，收工啦？
uncle, are you off?
我在开工
I'm still working
好大罐头味
I smell something canny
老婆，又吃罐头？
honey, canned food again?
爸爸
Daddy!
叫世伯！没那么碍耳
Call me uncle! It sounds better!
世伯，有罐头吃已经很好了
Uncle, canned food is better than nothing
我很多时连冷饭菜汁都没得吃
I don't even have rotten vegetables to eat sometime
我妈很烂赌  只喜欢打麻将，买六合彩
my mom loves to gamble, playing mahjong and Mark six
不喜欢煮饭
she doesn't like to cook
女人烂赌很讨厌呀
it's disgusting!
这件事我支持你
You're absolutely right
你怎么看法，伯母？
what do you think, aunt?
你没有手，自已不会煮呀？
You have hands, why didn't you cook?
自己煮？  男人煮饭，给人喝倒采的
Cook, myself? And have people laugh at me?
今天的女人是不会待在厨房的
Today's woman won't be your servant
因为今天的女人还没有遇到明天的男人
because today is woman hasn't meet tomorrow's man
你要听世拍的忠告
listen to my warning
我的女儿不适合你
my daughter is not suitable for you
适合，我和美亚很投契
suitable. May and myself are perfect together
我们是天生一对
we are two of a kind
我叫“怕丑草”，她叫“交际花”
I'm shy grass, she's a flower girl
阿叔
Uncle!
我吃饭  你煮饭
I'm rice, and you're the rice cooker
他上了身呀
There's something wrong!
他会神打吗？
Voodoo!
美亚，过来
Mia!
笑口枣
Smiley Joe!
扭屁股都有的
Look at him swing his butt
难看死
what an ugly sight!
-拜拜  -拜拜
Bye!
姐姐，你忘记拿手袋
Sis, you forgot your purse
-谢谢  -拜拜
Thank you, Bye
真是老土
stupid!
玩得开心一点
Have a good time!
玩得小心一点
But be careful!
几多号呀？
What number?
二十六
二十六，继续啦...
26, continue...!
跳舞比赛怎么样？
How's the dance contest?
输了
I lost!
那些男人真卑鄙
Those men are real low!
干什么？跟油脂仔吵架？
What happened? Quarreled with that punk?
岂止吵架，简直绝交呀
More than that. We are now strangers!
他跳舞踩到你条尾呀
Did he step on you while dancing?
好气呀
I'm mad!
刚才跳完舞我们去吃饭
After we danced I wanted to go eat
他目不转睛望住女侍应的大腿
and he was just staring at the waitress thighs
菜单写在女侍应生的大腿上？
the menu was on her thighs?
干嘛你不即刻走，
Why didn't you leave on the spot?
我没有那么蠢
I wasn't that stupid!
两百五十块
250 bucks!
再叫一个纽西兰生蚝  两百八十块
And then rock oysters from New Zealand. 280 bucks
王菜是焗龙虾  四百八十块
the maim course was baked lobster, 480 bucks
还有吃甜品
and there was dessert
他破产啦
he must be broke!
那么多好东西吃
It's such a big meal,
你应该打电话回来  叫我们一齐去吃
you should have called and invited us
我吃了他一千多块
I ate away more than a thousand bucks
离去时才跟他说分手
and told him to get lost after he paid the bill
聪明女，有性格
good girl. You've got character!
有你妈当年的风范
You're just like mom in the old days
他很老土，还追我出餐厅
he went after me, after we left toe restaurant
我就当街打他一巴掌
and I gave him a slap on the face
好极了  虎母无犬女
that's wonderful... you're just like me!
当年我就是这样对付你老爸
That's what I did to your dad back then!
肥妹，别丑化我的形象
Fatty, don't distort my image
-改天我教多几招给你  -好啊
I'll tell you more some other time
什么号码？
what's your number?
-十五呀  -十五
15, 15
这样选号码可以吗？
Does it really work?
童子手，很灵的。搞掂
I'm sure it does!
收抬东西回房睡觉
Pack your stuff and go to sleep
老公，我们的新房子真是豪华
Honey, our new room is really great
你在楼上享受成怎么样？
how's it upstairs?
这儿很舒服
It's really comfortable here
以前在冲凉缸要放好多个屁
I had to fart a lot before
才有这种效果
to get this sort of effect
快点下来  舞会就要开始了
come down quickly. The party's beginning
阿三，阿四  食物准备好没有？
ah Sam, ah say! Get the food ready?
差不多了，主人
It's almost ready, master!
到底好了没有
Either it's ready or not!
快点去厨房做事
Go to the kitchen and get things ready
是，主人
yes! Master!
今晚的烟花准备好没有？
Are tonight fireworks ready?
准备好
Yes!
-试放一次  -是
Test it once!
好豪华啊
Wow! What a luxury!
今晚的宾客一定大开眼界
Tonight guests will be really amazed
爸爸，妈咪，过来看
daddy, mommy, come take a look!
我真不明白
I don't understand
为什么你以双倍价钱收购“会疯很行”？
why did you pay twice the amount for crazy bank?
没什么，贪过瘾
Just for fun!
谢谢
Thnak
不算贵了，小意思，不算贵
Not expensive, very cheap!
小心点，不要弄肮脏我的地毯
Be careful, don't dirty my carpet
失礼人家啊，来
It's...
我的古董花瓶很贵的  小心打破
be careful don't break my antique flower vases!
喂
Hello
你们怎么还没来
Why are you here yet? Hurry up!
各位嘉宾，今晚除了我们新居入伙
honorable guests, besides being a housewarming
还庆祝我妹妹得到模型比赛冠军
we are celebrating my sister's first prize
现在由她来示范运作她的模型
now, she will demonstrate how her model works
她这次得奖的模型就是
and winning model is...
大浪湾核电厂
Tai long wan nuclear power plant
核电厂？
nuclear power plant?
伟大
Great
议员  你们用不着出外考察核电厂
Councilmen, there's no need to research nuclear plant
留在这里考察我这个天才儿童的核电厂
all you have to do is look at this model,
再写报告不是更好
your reports taken from it would be even better
妈咪，爸爸
mon, dad!
什么事？
What happened?
我离了婚
I got a divorce
-笑口枣呢？  -为什么？
where's smiley Joe?
一出海，他就看住“金丝猫”
As soon as we left port he hooked on to a blonde
气死我啦
it really pissed me off!
辐射啊
The radiation...
没事的，十公尺范围以内都不会有辐射
It's alright. There won't be any radiation within 10 metres.
快点走啊
Let's go quick...
走啦，女儿，快点
Let's go, girls. Hurry up!
开门啊
Open the door...
请先让车上的乘客下车
Please let the passengers get off first
-不要站近车门  -挤不进就不要进来啦
Don't go near the tram doors
离谱一点吧
It's...
下一站是中环
The next station is "chung wan" oh, "central"
我
I
好闷呀，透不到气
It's very stuffy. I can't breathe
骠叔
Uncle bill!
骠叔去了哪儿？
Where is Uncle bill!
他一回来就去了洗手间
He went to the washroom
他出来了
he's out!
刚才那个女人吐
but the woman just...
看你译的这篇稿
Look at your translation
一九六四年甘乃迪谋杀案  什么东西？
"the 1964 Kennedy murder case". What is this?
甘乃迪谋杀案
It should be "the Kennedy-was-murdered case"
你识不识文法的
don't you know grammar?
这叫做被动词
This is called a "passive verb"
再说一遍
repeat it!
被动词
"Passive verb"...
拿回去改
Take it back and revise it
好痛呀
It hurts!
你怎么了啦，没事吧？
How are you? Are you alright?
-怎么了，没事吧？
My stomach!
-好肚痛呀
You okay?
搅肠沙，肚子痛
She's got a stomach ache
-快送她去医院  -帮忙
quick send her to the hospital
新闻部还有一分钟直播
the news will be on air in one minute
总控制室  播多两首歌顶住几分钟
vtr control, would you play a couple of songs
画面定了  导演随机应变
can't do. The producer has to do something!
骠叔，待会一段财经，你报告了
Uncle bill, you're going to do the financial report
他报告？
him?
你还不怕，他还犯错不够
Hasn't tie made enough mistakes?
他已经错很多次了
He's screwed up so many times
这种人是不可以相信的
you just cannot trust this kind of people
我来报告
I'll do it
新闻音仔直播倒数十秒
10 seconds to news live
十，九，八，七，六
10, 9, 8...
五，四，三，二，一
54,3,2,1
各位观众，现在报告午间新闻
hello, viewers! You are just tuning into the afternoon news.
三四五六七八...
3,4,5,6,7,8...
一...到我老公报告新闻了
1... and now here's my husband reporting the news.
熊猫D0D0证实没有休孕
Dodo the panda has been proven that she is not pregnant.
经过上次小产  DoDo一度有怀孕的迹象
Since the miscarriage from last time, dodo has been showing signs of pregnancy.
动物园万面认为
The zoo has reason to believe that
熊猫D0D0现正处干求偶期间
dodo the panda is currently in a state of finding another mate.
所以最近它的脾气显得特别暴躁
That is why she has been very tempermental lately.
继续由女魔头报告财经
Miss lui mor is going to report the financial news
特写女魔头
close-up on the witch!
本港股市方面
And now on the Hong Kong stock market.
自从八四年八月开始上升以来
Since the rise of the stock market in August 1984,
不断创出新高峰
it has continually made new records.
恒生指数上周创下一九九七的纪录
The hang seng index has hit a record of 1997 last week.
中段更加一度冲破二千点
It had even reached the 2000 point in between.
多个恒生成分股例如长江实业
Other investers for the heng seng including cheung Kong realty,
和记黄埔，置地，九仓等
hutchison, and etc
与上一年年底比较
have increased 30%
均上升一到三成
since the end of last year.
与两年前产生危机的时候比较
There has even been a 3-5 times increase
更加上升三到五倍
in contrast to the crisis from two years ago.
-期指万面...
In other news...
-新闻部录影厂最后两分钟
Last two minutes on the news broadcast.
成交也缩减到三千
The trade has also been decreased to 3000...
现货在九月
In September...
怎么会影住两个人的？
How come it's a two-shot?
跳了掣
One of the buttons got jammed!
我找人来修理
I'll find someone to fix it
人都跑光了
everybody's gone
影住两个人出街算了
the 2-shot is on air
黄金卖买万面
国际金价经过昨天获利回扣之后
今天在亚洲市场站稳
徘徊在三百三至五百美元之间
美元经过昨天反弹之后
今天又再回落
我不知道
I don't know
骠叔疯了  找人阻止他
uncle bill is crazy. Find someone to stop him
收市七点七八九零
上午银行同业拆息是偏低的
美国和西德联手减息消息
-对美元只是产生短暂的支持作用  -死了
仍然是不看好
Damn! This machine doesn't work!
-投资者对美国的经济指标  -怎么看到我的
今日的新闻跟财经已经报导完毕
That's the end of the news and financial report
谢谢各位收看
thank you for watching!
你死定
You are dead!
骠叔，今天有什么新闻？
Uncle bill, what's the big news today?
今天的新闻就是以后我不用报告新闻
The news today is that I don't have to read the news
他出去了
he's out to town!
我今天早上还见过他
But I just saw him this morning
他刚走  要一个礼拜才回来
he just left. Won't be back until a week later
宝玲...你的盒好漂亮
Your box is pretty
里面的更漂亮
what's inside is much prettier
我三天前已经做好了
it was finished three days ago
你一定拿第一啦
you've got get first place!
你预备钱请我喝庆功奶昔
Let your money ready to take me out for a milkshake
老师，放在哪儿
miss, where should I put this?
放在最后边的那张桌子上
Put it on the last table
你猜这火山上活的还是死的
guess whether this volcano is active or inactive?
我就希望它是死了
I hope that it's inactive
你看
look!
我这个钟全部齿轮都是用木做的
This entire clock is made of wood
成功啦
it works!
你什么都“哗”的？
Why do you always say "wow"?
对不起
Sorry!
你不要老是“哗哗”声好不好？
Don't say "wow" all the time, okay?
我忍不住
I can't help it
给我看看你的设计  我想开开眼界
let me take a look at your project I want to see it
先看你那个
let me see yours first
你在哪儿买的
where did you make this?
我自己做的
I made it myself
是玩具又不是科学模型
it's a toy not a science project
它最科学就是这个马达
his science project is a motor
是由太阳能发电
it runs of soiar power
电筒都可以
a flash light works also
你哥哥帮你做的？
did your brothers help you?
不是，我自己一手一脚做的
No, I did it all by myself
宝玲你看
look!
宝玲，你设计了什么？
What did you make?
太阳系
A model of our solar system
太阳系？我四年级已经做过了
model of the solar system? I made that in primary 4
我那个太阳装了电灯胆  会发光的
I my model, the sun was illuminated by a light bulb
九大行星可以自转
with the nine planets revising on their own
还有哈雷彗星
and all of their moons in tow
不过比起我今天这个就小儿科了
but compared to this project that one was nothing
拿走吧
take it away!
我这个机械人有发声系统的
This robot operates off a specific sound
你失败了
ha! It doesn't work!
动
Move!
你看看！宝玲
Look at it!
好棒呀
Great...!
不要拍手了，它痴线了
Stop clapping, it going to short out
宝玲，你破坏了我的发声系统
you destroyed my project
-动...  -怎么样，是不是坏了
...
可以修好吗？
动
...
老师，我可不可以过两天才交？
Miss, can I hand you my project two days later?
但是比赛说过今天交作品的
The contest is today you've to hand in your project
我还有很多新构思呀
I still have lots of ideas!
你肯改进是好的
It's good to add more detail
但是我要对其他同学公平
I have to be fair to the rest of your classmates
老师呀
miss!
开始评分啦，回去吧
We're going to start judging back to your seats
工厂妹
factory girl!
二索，糊了
Two stripes, I win!
-现在是报告...  -电视人渣
Television addict!
老婆呀！买只竹丝鸡
Honey
买两片回来炖
buy a chicken and two wings to stew
你还好意思说
aren't you embarrassed?
你现在被人炒了鱿鱼
You've been fired
餐餐吃谷种，你知不知道
don't you know we're almost out of food?
这些日子我情绪低落
I'm feeling depressed these days
当然想吃好的东西
so I want something good to eat
脸无血色，怎去见工呢？
how can I look for work looking so pale?
病欺人穷的，越穷越要补
You've to eat better if you are poor a in ill-health
对！对！钱呢？
right! Right! What about the money?
钱？钱就没有
Money? We've got none!
你安心好了
It would be shameful to buy bean sprouts everyday
切块肥叉烧
cut a piece of barbecue pork
快点把钱收起来
hurry up, get the money
冯先生，你不用问我们借钱
Mr. fung, don't ask us to borrow any money
我们穷得只打筹码而已
we're so poor, we'll even take poker chips!
你想借钱  最好找骠叔啦
You want to borrow money, the best is to ask uncle bill
-骠叔是最大方的  -是呀
uncle bill is the most charitable
骠叔
uncle bill
我是老冯呀
it's me, Mr. fung!
那么好在家呀
Oh how nice, you're at home!
放大假
On vacation!
这些日子我手头很紧
These days I'm running short too
老婆又走掉了
my wife left
你们豪门大户  真是羡煞旁人，我想...
you guys are so well off that I envy you. I want...
-想借钱是吗？  -是呀
Want to borrow money?
借钱没问题
No problem
这儿五百块
here's five hundred, take it!
所谓远亲不如近邻
that's what neighbors are for
这些钱是雪中送炭，拿去用
lending money is like sharing coals during winter
骠叔，你说得真是对
uncle bill, you're right
如果人人学你这样
if everyone were like you
我就发财了
then I'd be rich
有钱记得还呀，老冯
remember to pay me back when you have toe money!
骠婶，我真是感激你
Auntie Lydia, I appreciate it
什么事？
what?
在我饥寒交迫的时候
During me times of difficulty
骠叔借了五百块给我开饭
uncle bill lent me five hundred so that we could eat
真是谢谢啦
thank you so much!
我赶住去吃牛扒
I'm going out for a steak, see you later
是呀，又大方，又肯帮人
right, generous and willing to help others
应该的！应该的！
that's the way it should be!
-死佬  -骠叔真是好人
Bill!
最多不吃
Worse comes to worse, we don't eat
是不是借了五百块给老冯？
did you lend five hundred dollars to Mr. fung?
缩脚...拖地呀
Move your feet, I'm mopping the floor!
妈咪，不要阻住我呀
Mommy, you're in my way!
是谁阻住谁呀？
Who's in who's way?
是对六合彩的时候了
We won the Mark six
我借钱给人你就打得我全身淤
I lent someone money you give me bruises all over
你自己就去买六合彩
but you yourself go out and buy Mark six tickets
你借钱给人没得回头
when you lend someone money, what do you get out of it?
-我买六合彩有得搏呀  -妈咪呀
At least when I buy Mark six, there's a chance of win
-搏？没有搏到已经吃拳头  -爸爸呀
chance? When we lose I punched out
搏到不是要挨砖头？
what if we win? I get hit over the head with a brick
当住女儿的面说我的不是
you're scolding me in front of our daughters
你怕吃砖头，不要对了
you're afraid of the bricks, forget about the Mark six
为什么不对？
why forget about it?
给钱买的，怎么也要搏一搏！
We use money to buy it, we got to take a risk!
我的
That's mine!
你买那么多
You bought so many
怪不得我们餐餐吃炒芽菜
no wonder we have been sprouts for every meal
看住
look!
第一个搅出来的号码就是，二十二号
The first number is "22"
-二＋二...  -二十二...
22, 22
这一张二十二，发财
we've got one ticket with "22"!
观音圣母玛利亚
Hail Mary, full of grace
千谢，万谢让我中一次
a thousand thanks, a million thanks. I hope I win
我不贪心的  中一次就够了，谢谢
I'm not greedy, I just hope to win once
第二个搅出来的号码就是，六号
the second number is "6"
六号。我又中了
number "6", I win again, I got to two numbers
中了两个  发啦...发过周润发
we've going to be rich richer than chow yun fat
第三个搅出来的号码就是，四十号
the third number is "40"
四十，我中了三个号码
I've got three number
发啦...发过基本法
we've going to be rich beyond our wildest dreams
冷静
calm down!
第三个号码已搅出来，跟住那三个号码谁中了
Three more numbers & someone will win the $15m grand prize
谁就是一千五百万得主
Who is...
好，大家留意第四个号码
stay, let's pay attention to what the fourth number
第四个搅出来的号码就是
the fourth number is...
现在重复最后三个号码就是
Now I will repeat the last three numbers
三十号，三十五号，三十九号
number 30, number 35,number 39
都不中
Do not.
中了三个就玩完了
Never...
各位，不要气焰
everyone, don't get discouraged
气馁呀！气焰
discouraged!
不要灰心，我们再来过
Don't get discouraged, we'll start again
老公，你先说
honey, you first
-我的心不舒服，五号  -五号
I got number 5!
-十号  -十号
10!
-顺口说，十五  -十五
While were at it, 15
-那我就二十啦！  -二十
number 20!
我自己就要二十五
I want number 25!
老公，你再说一个号码
Honey, pick another number
中三个字就玩完
if we hit here more numbers, three, zero please
老婆，如果真的中了  我就不用做了
Honey, if I win, then I don't need to work
你就想，明天就去找事做
don't day dream, look for a job tomorrow
小姐，再给我一杯咖啡
Miss, give me another cup of coffee
先生，已经第六杯了
mister, it's your sixth cup of coffee
喝那么多咖啡，你会不会手发抖？
are you going to get the shakes, drinking so much coffee?
冤气，先退房
Darling, go and check out
你很粘人的
You're sticking around me so much
碰到熟人，你等我一会
wait a moment, I ran into someone I knew
不要看过来
don't look over here
-骠叔  -经理
manager
你怎么知道我在这儿？
how did you know that I was here?
我找你很多天了
I've been looking for you for a couple of days
你找到来这里
how did you find me here?
我找得你很辛苦  他们说你出外埠
I have been looking for you, and you are out
想不到在这儿见到你
but by coincidence I ran into you here
又见到她
I saw her again
究竟你找我有什么事？
why are you looking for me?
她炒了我鱿鱼
She fired me!
以后我就不可以跟随你左右
From now on I can't follow you
所以我觉得不安心
that's why I feel more relieved
不安心，说话就糊里糊涂
and if I am worried, then I get confused when I talk
不清不楚，不三不四，会乱说话
unclear, and bullshitting all the time
你别说了，今晚回新闻部复职
don't mention it, tonight go back to work
这样不太好
this is no good, seems like I'm forcing you
现在不是你威胁我
you're not blackmailing me
是我威胁你来你威胁我呀
I'm blackmailing you so that you can blackmail me
你威胁我？
are you blackmailing me?
是我威胁自己威胁你来威胁我
I'm black mailing myself to blackmailing you to blackmail me
反正今晚立刻上班
anyway, you got to work tonight
不理谁威胁谁
no matter who blackmails who,
总之谢谢经理
anyway, thanks!
老婆，那些孩子去了什么地方？
Honey, where have the children gone?
还没放学
Not back from school yet
我说个好消息给你听
I have good news for you
经理说请我回去做
the manager asked me to go back to work
由今晚开始  回去新闻部报告新闻
starting from tonight, I go back to reporting the news
好啊  前几天我在黄大仙求了支上上签
a couple of days ago I went to wong tai sin
我就知道会走运了
I knew we were going to be lucky
现在守得云开见月明
now the time is on our side
老公，来
honey, come here!
窝麻炖九天翅
I know you're going to like this shark's fin soup
你一定喜欢吃。还有一支X0  来吧
and also this xo, come!
老婆，你太过份了
Honey, you're too much!
我还没上班
I'm still not back at work, not yet getting a salary
干嘛笑得那么姣
why are you laughing at me like that?
你说我姣呀  从哪儿来钱买这些东西
You idiot, what's wrong with my laugh?
私房钱
It's my own allowance
你肯用私房钱来买这么好的东西给我吃
you're willing to use your money to buy expensive food
老公，我知道以前对你不好
honey, I knew I was wrong in the past
所以今天给你吃个饱
that's why today, you will be fed like a king
用不明来历的钱买来的东西
who knows where you got the money, I'm not going to eat
肮脏钱？
Dirty money?
怪不得你近来笑得那么姣
No wonder these days your laugh is so sexy
我明啦，嫌我穷
I understand, you don't like it because I'm poor
在外面认识了第二个男人
you met another guy!
神经病  我都不知道你说什么
You idiot, I don't know what you are talking about?
这些东西值一千多块钱
This stuff cost $1000
如果你有千多块  发你的横财梦
with $1000,you would have premed your hair
你见钱开眼，财迷心窍
your eyes widen when you see money
-拜金主义，你会益我  -去看看什么事
you're too practical I won't getting thing from it
世风日下  -为了钱，你出卖自己的灵魂  -不要吵啊
what a hell. For money you would sell yourself
你简直是无耻
you have no values
别说了
shut up!
你这样是逼我向你摊牌
You're trying to force me to lay down all the cards
我也知道瞒不住你
I know I can't hide anything from you
你终干肯承认了
finally you admit it
我说出来  你要受得住这个刺激才好
if I tell you, you better be able to handle it
真的有第三者
there's really a third person
老实跟你说，我...
I'll tell you the truth, I...
中了六合彩呀
Won the Mark six!
中了
You win?
听不到
I can't hear!
-老婆，你是不是真的中了六合彩  -是啊
Henny
十九万呀
$190,000!
十九万
$190,000?
我这辈子从来没有过那么多钱
I've never seen that much money in my whole life
老婆，等钱拿回来之后
honey, wait until we got the money
我们数呀数呀  数多几天，过足瘾之后
we'll count the money
然后一起去花，肥妹
until you're satisfied!
什么？什么一起花
What do you mean we'll spend it together?
这张六合彩是我自己一个人去买的  还分彼此你我
I bought this Mark six myself. Doesn't belong to you
你的不就是我的
yours is mine!
我的钱是偷男人得来的，肮脏的
My money is from other guys, it's dirty
肮脏不要紧
it doesn't matter if it's dirty
我们一起把它洗干净不就行了
we wash it together and it will be fine
是臭的
it stinks!
香的
It's smells good!
你说话真是岂有此理
You really know how to turn words around
我们女人就不会有钱了
women usually don't have money
连买六合彩都不会中
we can't win the Mark six
老婆，我不过是乱说话
honey, I was just kidding
像你这样怎么偷男人呀
a woman like you, you wouldn't have affairs
你是说我不够吸引力了
you mean I'm not attractive
不是，你现在很有吸引力
no, you are!
老婆...我不可以没有你
Honey, I need you
我真的是死心塌地地爱你，老婆
I am really love you, honey!
十九万，你以为钱少
$190,000 is a lot of money?
骠叔，这是最后一次机会
Uncle bill, this is your last chance
你行就行，不行的话，你就自动消失
if you don't take it, then disappear
我原谅她的
I'll give forgive him
她一年不可能赚到十九万，对吗？
it's impossible for her to make $190,000 in one year, right?
请多多指教
I'd like to learn how?
熊猫D0D0终于怀孕
Dodo the panda is finally pregnant
-这件事令动物园的人非常高兴  -财务员，叫他说快点
people at the zoo are extremely happy
财经之前是六合彩的消息
before the economic review it's the Mark six news
今期的搅珠号码是
the winning numbers for this week are
五，十，十五，二十，二十五，三十
5,10, 15, 20, 25, 30!
发达啦
I'm going to rich!
特别号码是三十
Spacel num is 30
头奖只有一注中
Only one person won
奖金系十九万九千七
the price is $199,700
不是呀
it's wrong!
是一千九百万
No, it's 19000,000!
一千九百万？
19 million?
是不是真的，老婆
Honey, is that for real?
真的，老公，是真的
Yes honey, yes!
一千九百万
19 million!
-一千九百万  -My God
19 million! My God.
笑什么？
Why are you laughing?
笑也不行
Can't I laugh!
各位观众
Ladies and gentlemen!
他...又来了
He's coming again!
电视台工我不想再做
I don't want to work here at the station anymore
电视台是剥削机构
the people in charge here are a group of scoundrels
欺压低薪职员
they pick on those who earn less than themselves
浪费了我十八年青春
I've wanted 18 years of youth
喂什么呀，八婆
what, woman?
尤其是这种人渣
Just like yourself, useless
持住跟总经理通奸
affairs with our station manager, as if it we're nothing
笑什么？发神经
Why are you laughing, idiot?
老公，明天我们找房子搬家
Honey, tomorrow we look for another house
我要住大房子
I want to live in a big house
以后都不要住这些白鸽笼
I will never live in such a small place again
搬大房子就是告诉人家我们发财了
if we buy a new house everyone will know we're rich
他们又要来借钱
people will come and borrow money from us
搬家可以静静的搬，是不是？
we can more secretly, right?
让我想想，睡吧
Let me think, go to sleep!
老公
Honey!
这个月不交房租给房屋署
needn't to pay this month's rent to the housing authority
可以赖租就尽量赖
if we don't have to pay, we won't
看他们加租加得那么过瘾
they increased the rental too much
好...睡吧
okay, let's sleep!
老公
Honey!
由明天开始
Starting from tomorrow
我天天炖鸡鲍翅给你送饭
you'll have shark's fin soup to go with your rice
龙虾做早餐，满意吗？
and lobster for your breakfast, okay?
很多胆固醇的
Too much cholesterol
-很容易会有心脏病的  -你怎么了
it's easy to get a heart attack
第一次听见你说不吃鸡鲍翅
what's the matter, you love shark's fin
睡吧
go to sleep!
老婆  你记住以后不要再跟她们打麻将了
Remember, starting from now don't play with them
万一你打得兴奋  什么都说了出来
if you get excited, you'll spill the beans
我不会说的
I won't say anything
你会的
you will!
这样好了  我明天拿东西去当
Okay, tomorrow I will take things to the pawn shop
让他们以为我们很穷，好吗？
to let people to know that we are poor
这个办法也很好
this is a good idea
睡吧
let's sleep!
你在想什么？
What are you thinking about?
没想什么
What am I thinking about?
你以为我不知道
You think that I don't know,
饱暖思淫欲，发达最好死老婆
now that we're rich, you want me deal?
是不是  老婆，你那么肥大怎么会死
You're so big, how are you going to die?
不准你想女人
I won't let you think about other girls
-不想，睡
I won't, sleep!
I won't sleep!
老公
Honey!
衰佬
Dead beat!
举手
Hands up!
老婆，我错了
Honey, I know I'm wrong
发达也不敢想你死了
just because we're rich. I don't want you to die
美亚  美亚
Mia...
我找到美亚  美亚在那里呀
I found Mia
只有她一个在
she's by herself
姐姐，新泳池下水了
sis, we got a new swimming pool, let's go in?
你的新房子，有没有我的份
Do I have a share in the new house?
你那么疼我，一定留个大房子给你
Because you like me you'll have a room for sure
这间是你的
this is for you
这间是老二的
this is for Jody
小心呀
be careful!
对不起
Sorry!
老大，你去别处晒太阳
Sis, where are you going for a tan?
你再在这里晒太阳的话  我的房子就建不成了
If you still have your tan here, my house won't be finished
除非沙滩上的男人都没有脚
unless all the guys are legless
笑口枣，你弄坏我的房子
you ruined my castle
对不起
I'm ss 0 rry!
美亚
Mia...
上次在餐厅是我不对
I was wrong in the restaurant last time
你走啦，小笼包，陈世美，没有良心
you go away. Heartless!
窦雪糕...快点
Go for an ice-cream, hurry!
姐姐，你不要心软呀
Sis, don't be too soft!
餐厅的女孩子看厌了
Tire of the girls at the restaurant
现在来看沙滩那些
and now come to the beach to look
上次你误会我了
you misunderstood me
我只不过看女侍应大腿上的那粒痣
I just looked at the mole on the waitress's leg
我还以为是苍蝇
I thought that was a fly
后来奇怪她为什么不痒？
she didn't feel itchy at all
我看真一点，原来真是痣
and closely, I realized that it was a mole
现在沙滩上那么多女孩子的脚上都有痣
here are a lot of girls who have moles on their legs
你不去看是不是苍蝇
why don't you go check whether it is a fly or not?
看过了  那些不是痣而是苍蝇
Look at it, it's no moles, those are flies
我才不理你
get lose!
兄弟...糟了，这次不行了
Buddy, it's not going to work
不行？我的的士更不行了
my car doesn't work too
为了送你来，现在车都坏了
because of you, my car's dead too
回去一定给老板炒鱿鱼
we've going to get fired for sure
做兄弟要有难同当
as buddies, we have to stick together
你们两个无论如何也要帮我这一次
no matter what you guys have to help me this time
行
go!
怎么样帮法？
How can I help?
小妹妹，一个人那么静呀
Why are you here alone?
让我来陪你
Let me be your companion
-晒得很漂亮
you have a very nice tan
-干什么？
what does it matter to you?
我们来调戏你
We are just pulling your leg
你不高兴？
you're unhappy, you've no boyfriend it's dangerous
没男朋友陪，很危险
Not boyF...
美亚...我来救你呀
I'm here to help you!
不用怕，我们暂时不会侵犯你的
Don't be afraid, we won't hurt you
迟些就很难说了
it's hard to say what will happen later
美亚...我来救你呀
I'm here to save you!
你们究竟想怎么样？
What the hell do you guys want?
我们很多事都想
We want you!
不过现在还没到时候
But it is not time yet
美亚，救你
help you!
救命呀
Help!
救我呀
Help me!
-笑口枣真是没用
Smiley Joe, that's embarrassing!
-走吧
Run!
笑口枣
Smiley Joe
美亚...
Mia...
我终干救到你啦
I finally rescued you!
-笑口枣
Smiley Joe
-美亚
Mia...
老大
Sis!
什么，你家中了六合彩？
Your family won the Mark six
是真的，有了钱我们就可以更浪漫了
yes, it's more romantic when one has money
我叫爸爸买只游艇给我们
I'll ask my dad to buy us a yacht
我跟你扬帆出海
we can go sailing!
过我们的二人世界
It will be us two only
好棒呀
mama Mia!
爸爸，你有明信片是六叔
Dad, you got a postcard
在马尼拉寄来给你的
our uncle six sent it from Manila
看看他写了什么
see what lie wrote!
他会有什么好写
It's probably nothing!
他说他会回来香港
He said he will visit Hong Kong
到时约你吃饭见面
and will have a dinner with you
好，你替我写封回信给他
good, help me to write a letter to him
叫他吃自己
go tell him to screw himself
爸爸，你们是两兄弟
dad, you guys are brothers
为什么不跟他吃饭
why not have a dinner with him?
你时常跟你讨厌的人吃饭
You always have dinner with people you don't like
那不同，你妈是我老婆
but that's different, your mother is my wife
我真不明白你那么讨厌六叔
I don't understand why you hate uncle so much!
你当然不明白
Of course you don't understand
你没有试过给人用辣椒油倒在裤子上
you've never had chili sauce poured into your pants
睡觉的时候给人划两个黑眼圈
or while sleeping, having circles drawn on your face
爸爸，你不是那么小气吧
dad, you not the unforgiving!
最离谱的是那一次
The worst time was
在我生日那天  他当住所有亲戚的面
during my birthday and in front of the relatives
把一个忌廉蛋糕扔在我的脸上
he tossed a cake into my face
他就笑得风凉啦
And he stood there and laughing
他就喜欢把快乐建筑在我的痛苦身上
he loves to watch me suffer
爸爸，我想买只游艇
dad, I want to buy a yacht
好，买啦
okay!
爸爸，你真好，谢谢你
Dad, you're great, thanks!
不用谢我
Don't thank me!
你自己给钱买
You have to pay for it yourself
我是说那二千万
I'm talking about the 20 million
我的钱不是这样用的
we won't spend our money like that
-爸爸
daddy
-爸爸，我有事跟你商量
dad, I got something to talk over
-爸爸
daddy
-你没商量，你有商量  拜拜
you got something to talk about, bye!
圣诞节我约了两个朋友去日本听演唱会
I'm going with my friends to Japan
不！不！
no! No!
我还没说完
I haven't finished
对我来说，你已经说完了
you're finished!
我约好了朋友去旅行
I've already invited my two friends to a picnic
旅行？去新娘潭
go to central park
你怕我花你的钱
you're afraid that I spent all the money
几个女孩子去日本很不安全的
it's not safe for girls to go to Japan alone
不会！我们去听“安全地带”
no!
那儿很安全的
We're going to a safe place!
你会说日本话
Can you speak Japanese?
说英文
I'll speak in english
日本人说英文只有日本人才会听
Japanese speak english only Japanese can understand
日本浴室是男女共浴
in Japan, boys and girls bath together
日本男人通街小便
and Japanese men piss all over the place
这种地方你不能去的
you can't go there
我们去原宿学艺
we're going to the university 1048?
去学松田圣子，菊池桃子
To imitate matsuda seiko and kikuchi momoko
如果我红了就发达了
if I become popular, then I'm rich!
最怕你学冈田有希子，跳楼自杀
You'll imitate okata yuhiko and commit suicide
我去了解日本的文化跟历史
I just going to check out Japanese culture & history
历史？你还说历史
history? You're talking about history?
什么历史都给日本人改掉了
The Japanese changed their history
记得九一八，一二八，香港三年零八
remember when toe Japanese attacked
-爸爸，你别那么八啦
dad, quit mumbling!
-还有  霸占了我们钓鱼台
Also, they've seized the island near east China
我们没地方钓鱼
we don't have anywhere to fish
别想去日本了
stop thinking about going to Japan
圣诞节我们回乡下去
we're going to China in Christmas
-回乡下？
to China?
-不好吗？  回乡下可以威风，衣锦还乡
Why not? If you go to China, people'll admire your clothes!
那么老土
What a bumpkin
去看看是不是老冯
go and see if that is Mr. fung
如果他来借钱，说我不在
if he comes here for money, tell him I'm not in
老公，你看我漂不漂亮
Honey, am I pretty?
看你把头弄成这样
That's your hairstyle!
我又剪又电，还做染发
I got it cut and permed, also high-line
才二千多块
only $2000
你真是败家
you're useless
“法兰西夜巴黎”，香不香？
this is "Paris", smells good?
还有件游泳衣，三点式的
Also my bikini!
是我的，我今年也要穿一次
That's mine, this year I'm going to wear that
这样才算跟得上潮流
so that I'm in fashion
-你想去那个海滩早点告诉我  -好的
so whichever beach you're going to, let me know first
我们把红旗插上去
so that we can ask them to put up a red flag?
你看你的头，好像北狮一样
Look at yourself, like a lion
当初我娶你都是因为你朴素
I married you back in the day because you looked casual.
现在你变成衣服的奴隶，化妆品的囚徒
Now you've become a slave to clothing and a prisoner of cosmetics.
姐姐，帮我擦
Sis, let me help you put it on
小妹呀，小心
honey, watch out!
-里边有粒钻石，要三千多块钱一瓶  -老婆
This diamond costs $3000
人穿衣服是用来顶冷的
honey, people wear clothes to keep warm
人的价值不是由衣服看出来的
you can't judge people from what they are wearing
做人要有内涵  要讲内在美
you have to look at the person's character
国货公司之能够屹立不倒
the China emporiums won't go bankrupt
因为它的东西又便宜又耐用
because their goods are good and durable
我们刚刚中了二千多万
we won 20 million dollars
难道带钱入棺材
we can't take to the coffin with us
真是妇人之见
don't be such a spendthrift
我们个个都没有储蓄的
no one in our household has an income
二千万只够我们五个人吃一辈子
$20m is enough for food during our lifetime
-爸爸  -这些钱不可以乱花
so we can't waste the money
整天追求享受
always looking for pleasure you'll be disappointed
今天你要买游艇  明天你要买邮船
today you'll need a yacht tomorrow an oceanliner
今天说要东游
today it's like this, tomorrow it's something else
-明天你就大话西游
daddy
-爸爸  今天变北狮
today, you're a lion
明天你就变河东狮
tomorrow, you'll be something else
老老实实，刚才我已经看中了一层楼
oh, by the way, I just found an apartment
买房子，我们这儿有什么不好？
an apartment? What's wrong with living here?
五百块一个月，去哪儿找？
Only $500 where can you find a place like this?
刚才我还拣了一辆平治车
Just now, I picked a Mercedes also
买车容易养车难，一阔三大
it's easy to buy a car but difficult to keep it up
你们听住，我打算投资移民
listen, I'm planning to emigrate
爸爸，你说过为“四个现代化”努力
China is modernizing!
你懂什么？
What do you know, we got so much money
君子不立危墙之下
a smart guy never sits under crumbing wall
现在不走，还待何时？
if we don't leave now, when are we leaving?
你错了
You are wrong
这笔钱大家都有份花的
everyone of us has the right to spend the money
你太善忘了  当初选号码，我选了两个
you so absent-minded, I picked two numbers
我是大股东  我有发言权
I'm the big shareholder, I make the decisions
抉择权，行使权
to decide or not to decide
抗议
not fair!
我们要民王
We want democracy!
中国人不流行这一套
Chinese don't like democracy!
我们要自由
We want freedom
银行的户口没钱，看你怎么自由
our bank a/c has no money, what do you mean freedom?
爸爸，你当我欠你的
Dad, I'll owe you the money
我算过了
I've already counted
从小到大，你欠我三十六万八千
since you were born to this moment, you owe me $368000
-你更多！还有你  -我...
you owe me even more! And you too!
你也欠我十三万八
You owe me $138000!
我会在你们的股份里扣除
I'll take it from your shares
从明天起，每人每天支三十六块钱花
starting from tomorrow you each get $36
做又三十六
whether you work,
不做又是三十六
or you don't, you get the same
发神经
You crazy! "Wishing hole"
老婆，还是你好
Honey, you're the best!
我当然好啦，睡吧
Of course I'm the best, go to sleep!
那里有很多汽水喝的
When we get there, there will be lots of sodas
可以不用喝家里的
don't drink what we have at home
你的西装很好看呀
your suit is great!
老冯，其实我们不是很风光
Mr. fung, we're not really that well off
穿得漂亮，只不过是虚有其表
clothes are just superficial
现在因为要去宴会
we have a banquet to go later
所以就要死充
that's why we have to do our best
其实我们很穷，你千万别误会
we're actually poor, I hope you don't mind
走啦
let's go!
-你知道就好了  -走啦  -街坊邻里知道也不要紧  -走啦
Since you know, I guess it's ok, if our neighbors know
他是不是问我还钱？
are you asking me to return your money?
游泳表演
I'm watching a swimming exhibition
-太太，喝点东西  -谢谢
...
-我这两个女儿学了韵律泳三个月  -是吗？
My two daughters have taken lessons for 3 months
教练就叫他们代表香港出赛
their instructor told them to represent Hong Kong
他们这个游泳的动作叫做“龙虾”
this styles is called "lobster"
-看看像不像  -很像呀
see if it looks like it yes!
神经，请我们上来
Idiot, they invite us to come,
汽水也不请我们喝
and not even serving us a drink
不要那么生气
don't be so upset
我们现在是二千万富翁
we now have $20m
他们才只有几百万
and they only got a couple of million
大量一点，不要跟他计较
don't worry about it, it's not worth it
香港的物价真是吓了我一跳
Hong Kong living standards are really amazing
你这间别墅这么贵
you estate is so expensive
表哥，你真是太阔气了
cousin, you're really generous
人生大半辈子都在房子里渡过
we lived here for over half of my lifetime
住要舒服一点，不要刻薄自己
comfortably, so why worry about anything
大哥
brother!
细叔
Uncle!
阿尊，上去跟你大哥叙叙旧，来
John, go and talk with your big brother!
-老公
Honey!
-亲弟弟来的
Baby brother!
原来大表哥，大表搜你们来了
Uncle, aunt, you're here!
你们坐在这儿，我也没看见你们
I didn't know you were sitting here!
你们的眼睛生得那么高  怎么会看到我们
You've always looking upward how can you see us?
大哥，大嫂
Brother, sister-in-law!
-细叔
Uncle!
-难得今天那么多亲友赏脸光临
It isn't easy to get so many relatives together
真的是“富在深山有远亲”
it helps if you have money
“穷在闹市无人问”
otherwise, we'd never see each other
还好我们现在不是穷人
luckily, we're no longer poor.
大表嫂，你这件旗袍真是漂亮
Aunt, your gown is really beautiful
上两次饮宴好像见你穿过
I think I saw the last two times we got together
手工又那么好  怪不得你每次饮都穿这件
the workmanship is so good, that is why you wear it everytime
我也是最后一次穿
this is the last tune I wear it
-天气一凉，我就穿皮草  -那么舍得
when it gets cool I'm gong to wear my mink coat
真的
really!
不然的话，怎么花得完我两千万家财
If not, then how can I spend the 20 million dollar
二千万
20 million?
是呀，前两天我中了...
Yes, a couple of days, ago, I...
她前两天中风，现在语无伦次
She had a stroke, she doesn't know what she's talking about
招呼不到
We have to meet our guests
迟些见
see you later
妈咪，那个游泳池很大
mommy, this pool is huge
不用羡慕
nothing to be envious about it
以后我们的更加大
later, ours will be even bigger
是她说，我没有说
she said it, not me
-快叫六叔呀
call sixth uncle!
-六叔
Sixth uncle!
最小的女儿？
Are you the youngest daughter?
好久不见，有空聚一聚
We haven't seen each other for a long time
算替你洗尘
we've got to celebrate
老公，好吗？
honey, how are you?
不如明天我请你们全家出去吃饭
I'll take your whole family for dinner tomorrow
出去吃就不必了
it's not necessary
明晚来我家吃饭
come to my house tomorrow night
好，我明天来打扰你们
okay, but it's going to be a bother
不打扰，最要紧你来
it's not bother, just come
早点到
come earlier!
玉置浩二呀
Tamachi kogi
不够劲呀
not good enough!
轻声一点
Lower your voice!
你的电视机那么差
You're so beautiful on TV
-我搭的士回家去看
I'm going to take a taxi back home to watch it
-我又去呀
I'm going too!
真是老土
Junk!
去日本那件事快说服你爸爸
About Japan remind your dad!
不然的话，我们不等你了
If you don't, we won't wait!
拜拜，弟弟
Bye, boy!
小声一点，八婆
Quiet down, bitch!
你再不关掉我炸了你那间房子
If you don't turn it down, I'm going to blow up your room
你转性了，真的请你弟弟回来吃饭
You've changed, inviting your brother for dinner?
是呀  还准备了好东西让他享受
Yes, I've prepare a great meal
走开呀
leave!
-女儿，什么事呀  -美亚
What's the matter?
-又说去看电影
I thought you said that we going to see a movie
-最衰是他
he's the worst
刚才买票的时候目不转睛望住售票员
he's staring at the ticket seller!
你很姣啊
You're so dirty-minded!
不是  我看他那粒痣
No, I was looking at her mole
最近我研究相学
recently, I've been looking into reading fortunes
相书说，人的痣生在不同部位
the book said, depending upon where the mole is located
会有不同的人生启采
that person has a certain and distinct fate
你为什么看他脑呀
why were looking at her chest?
因为他脑口有两粒痣
Because her chest had two moles
人人的脑前都有两颗痣的啦
each person has two "miles" on their chest
但是他那两粒特别大
but hers were especially big
这种相叫做胸怀大志
it means that she is especially confident
你很色呀
you're a pervert!
不是色呀  那个售票员是个男人
I'm not a pervert!
你是同性恋
You're gay!
是男人吗？
It was a man?
怎么我不知道
How come I didn't know?
笑口枣，让我来访问你
Smiley Joe, let me ask you something
你究竟是喜欢男人还是女人
do you like men, or women?
当然是女人啦
Women of course!
有什么证据？
Where's your proof?
我喜欢美亚
I like Mia!
-我真的很喜欢她
I really like her!
-非礼呀
Molester!
你这个色情狂
You're a pervert
你这个油脂仔，以后不准来找我女儿
you punk, don't come here looking my daughter
阿女，找男人有没有钱不要紧
daughter, a man doesn't need money
最要紧是他疼你，对你好
he only needs to love you and treat you well
-这样的男人送上门也别要  -美亚
as for other types of men, forget them!
那些男人真是卑鄙
Men are really shit heads!
这个电视机应该解剖
This TV should have been thrown away
声音
sound!
神经病
Crazy!
-影像
Picture!
-这只是非洲的狒狒
This is a chimpanzee from Africa
它虽然只有几个月大  你们看多有趣
it's only a couple of months old, look how cute it is
全开了，你还不死
it's on, you're in for it now!
为什么老二会上电视的？
Why is Jody on TV?
为什么会这样？
How come?
这个歌星那么面熟
This singer looks so familiar
骠叔的女儿上电视
uncle bill's daughter is on TV
我“采”
Jesus!
看完非洲的狒狒
We've finished watching the chimp
下次动物奇观带大家去看丹麦的金丝猫
the next zoological feature will be on Swedish foxes
真是老土
that's really stupid!
怎么会这样？
How come it's like this?
我不知道
I don't know!
大情圣驾到
Valentino's here!
我心底里心底里的一句
My hearts wants to say!
衰人
Hell!
摸什么呀  难听死了，死人
It sounds awful!
心中爱你，不管你要话再会
My heart loves you even if you say goodbye
快摸牌啦
pick a card!
-自摸，大三元  -唱什么，唱衰了
I won!
死油脂仔，我跟你绝交
You punk, go to hell!
你去死  不能死，他还有利用的价值
You can't, I can still use him
摸什么，笑口枣
touch what!
你是不是很喜欢我的女儿
Do you like my daughter a lot?
当然喜欢了
Of course, yes
到别处去拍吧
go some where else to shoot!
-你要答应我一件事
You have to answer me one thing
-答应你？
what?
我不是喜欢你
I don't like you!
你喜欢我女儿  要不要过我这一关
You like my daughter you have to pass my approval
要的...世伯，你说吧
yes, uncle, tell me!
你明天有没有空
Do you have time tomorrow?
很难说的
It's difficult to tell!
如果下午有事做，我上午就有空
Busy in afternoon, then I'm free in the morning!
如果上午有事做，我下午会有空
I'm busy in the morning then I'm free in afternoon!
如果上下午有事做
I'm still free at night time
我就要晚上有空
Tomorrow's Sunday, I'm free the whole day
拿纸笔出来，先记下来
get a pencil and paper, write it down
明天先去借一套饼店送货员的制服
I'm going to borrow a uniform tomorrow morning
然后就替我送个蛋糕
after which I will deliver cake
要不要打领带
did I need to wear a tie?
打不打领带没有关系
It doesn't matter!
怎么没有关系  穿得整齐一点，有贴士
Why? The better you dress the more tips you get
你不会有贴士的
you're not going to get any tips
你去买个忌廉蛋糕
you have to go buy the cream cake
要不要写生日快乐
does it have to say "happy birthday"?
什么都不用写  最要紧是多点忌廉
No, it just has to have cream!
不打领带，没有贴士，多忌廉
No tie, no tips, more cream
到时候把蛋糕送上来我家
send the cake to my house tomorrow
-送上来我家
send it to my house
-是我家
my house!
就是我家嘛
You mean my house!
-就写你家吧  -就写你家吧
Just write your home address!
认住这个人
Remember this person
一见到他就用蛋糕向他脸上扔上去
when you see him throw the cake into his face
过瘾啦
it's going to be great!
怪不得没有贴士
No wonder there's not going to have any tips
这个机会等了十年
I've been waiting for this opportunity for ten years
大哥
brother!
你以为还是以前
You thought that it is the same as before?
-细叔，来弟，来，叫细叔啦  -细叔
Come here, say hello to uncle!
这个是我的二女
This is ray second daughter
这个是我大女儿带弟
this is my eldest daughter
六叔
uncle!
她干什么？
What was happened?
她跟男朋友吵架
She was arguing with her boyfriend
整天哭哭啼啼，真丢人
always crying, what a shame!
-细叔  -乖，这些礼物是送给你们的
Good girl, here's a present for you
-谢谢细叔...  -说谢谢吧
thank you, uncle!
小心呀，里面可能是死老鼠
Be careful, there might be a mouse inside
这些丑事你还记得
you still remember that time?
当然记得啦
Of course I remember!
跟你一起长大  我简直是忍辱偷生
Growing up with you, I had to endure a lot
老公，不要这样
don't do that
大哥，我为以前的事向你道歉
brother, I want to apologize for the things before
你从来都不肯向人道歉的
you never apologize!
我今天一定要说
I got to say it today
因为我时日无多
because I'm getting old
就快不久于人世
and don't have much time
又不知耍什么花样来作弄我们
what's he up to now?
我是说真的
I'm serious this time!
我患了脚癌
I have leg cancer
医生说我只有几个月命
the doctor said I have a few of months left to live
你们是我最亲的人
you're my closest relative
所以今晚一定要告诉你们两个
so tonight, I must talk to both of you
好啊...太好了
okay, fine!
真是开心呀
I'm really happy!
真是可怜，那么年青还没娶老婆
It's tragic, so young and still unmarried
我一直都当他是仇人  没有好好待他
I always thought of him as an enemy
今次见面可能是最后一次
this time could be the last time we saw each other
忍住，不要流眼泪出来
control yourself, don't cry
我忍不住
I can't control myself
-带弟，你吃不吃得下饭？  -你先坐
Are you going to eat?
-不吃了  -一起坐
No, I'm not going to eat!
-还好没有替你准备  -一起
Good thing. I didn't prepare anything for you
来弟，你看汤好了没有？
go and see whether the soup is ready
-吃饭了，细叔  -好的
- uncle! Eat please - Brother, sister-in-law!
大哥大嫂  你们有没有想买房子和车？
Have you ever thought of buying a house and a car?
有呀，有呀，你有什么办法？
Yes, yes, why?
我在恒丰银行做了十几年
I've been working with hang fung bank for 10 years
剩下很多优惠配额  我可以全给你们
I still have jots of "quartz" I can give it to you
买车，买房子的利息会算得很低
that way you can get a better interest rate
希望大哥大嫂能够接受我这心意
I hope that you accept my offer
喝碗鸡脚汤，以形补形呀
drink the chicken's feet soup, it's good for your leg!
快来坐下
Come and sit down!
吃饭啦
Eat...
怎么你们吃饭吃得这么闷呀
It's good to eat like this!
我来说个笑话给你们听  -很好笑的
Let me tell you guys a joke!
-好啊
Please!
从前有个男人他左脚生癌
Once upon a time, there was this guy
这是笑话吗？
is this a joke?
很好笑的  那个病患去医院做手术
This patient went to hospital for operation
切了一只左脚
he cut off his left leg
手术之后，病人醒来
after the operation, he woke up
见到医生愁眉苦脸对住他
he saw the doctor and he had a worried look
那个医生说  我有个好消息，一个坏消息
the doctor said, "I've good news and bad news"
你想先听哪个
"which one do you want to hear first?"
病患说，先说个坏消息来听
The patient said, "tell me the bad news first"
医生说，坏消息是我切错了你的右脚
the bad news is, "I cut off the wrong leg"
那好消息呢？
what's the good news?
医生说好消息就是你左脚没有生癌
"There was nothing wrong with your left leg"
-进来替我倒酱油
Come here and pour the soy sauce for me
-和我一起去拿酱油碟
hand me the soy sauce plate
倒酱油哪用四个人去
you don't need four people to pour soy sauce?
我跟你说，不要乱说话
Listen, be careful of what you say
我们今晚要好好的待他
tonight we must treat him well
不止今晚以后也要
not only tonight, but from now on
让我来开
let me open it
你找哪位
who are you looking for?
-找你啊
You!
-笑口枣  不要啊
Don't...!
是他啦...
Is him!
真是过瘾呀
It's funny!
开这样的车出去，头都可以抬高一点
You can lift your head a little higher, driving a car like this.
不用你自己开，请司机
You don't have to drive yourself hire a chauffeur
岂不是又要花钱
that means we have to spend money?
用我的优惠配额去买这架车，便宜一半
Use my "quartz" to hire him
车价也值回了
the car costs less than original price
老公，有了司机我们的头抬得更高
we hire a chauffeur, we going to be even more proud
这个游泳池好大  我喜欢
mommy, this swimming pool is big, I like it
大是够大
of course it's big
买车，买房，只剩下千多万
after buying a house and car, there's only $10m left
最好存在我的银行
it's best to save in my bank
我替你做外币存款
put it in a foreign accounts 18% interest for you
吃都吃不完
it'll never be able to use it all!
我还可以替你看管住
I could help you keep an eye on it
那种外币升值那就帮你买那种
interest goes up on other accounts, I'll help you swift
发财啦，老婆。钱会生钱的
we're going to be rich, money from money
只可惜我看不到多少
it's too bad I won't be around that long
不要摇，人摇福薄
don't shake your leg, you can't have money
跷脚会穷的
you'll be poor if you shake it a lot
老顽固
you're so stubborn
来弟，当我知道自己患了脚癌
when I knew I had leg cancer
就快不久于人世
and had a few months to live
我很想拍一套宣传片
I wanted to do a film
告诉我的亲朋戚友听
to tell all my relatives
不要跷脚
never to shake your leg
无论怎么样千万不要跷脚
no matter what
如果当初我没有跷脚
if I didn't shake my leg in the past
我根本不会坐在这儿
I wouldn't be sitting here now
跟你们说关干我生脚癌的事
and telling you about my leg cancer
不用伤心
don't worry!
细叔  得失是天数
Uncle, this is fate
生命和金钱一样
life and money is the same
有就有，没有就没有，这是天意
if you have it, you have it. That's fate
原来你们真的来看新房子
you guys come here to see the new house
我还以为你骗我
thought you lied to me
这间屋子真漂亮，一定有我的份儿
this is a very pretty house, can I stay here?
-你姐姐呢？
Where's your sister?
-在屋子里
Inside the house
-不准进去  -为什么？
you can't go in!
这间房子你有资格进去吗？
Do you have to ask to enter this house?
你是什么身份？
What's your status?
小便都可以吧
I'm just going to wash room, ok?
可以，花王间房有厕所
Yes, there is wash room in that room
哪儿可以小解？
Where can I go take a piss?
-里面  -谢谢
- Inside! - Thanks!
-这种小伙子我看他不会有出息
I don't think this guy has much of a future
-是不是笑口枣来了？
is smiley Joe come here?
是呀，去了厕所
Yes, he's is the bathroom
你看你男朋友真丢人
you boy-friend is an embarrassment
厕所很大呀
This bathroom is big!
-你没拉裤链  -对
You didn't zip up your sipper!
美亚
Mia
你怎么可以这样小解
How can you piss like that?
小便只有一个办法
There's only one way to piss
你露体狂
you streaker!
不露体怎么小便
If I don't streak, how can I piss?
难道隔住裤子吗？
How can I piss with my pants in the way?
你走，你下流
Get lost, you jerk!
小便也下流
Just because I piss, I'm not jerk
你下流
you jerk...!
色狼
Pervert!
原来你不止露体狂，还是色隋狂
You are not only a streaker, you a pervert too
你误会了
you misunderstand
你追我的女儿就是想沾我的家产
you date my daughter because you want my inheritance
你以为我不知道
you thought that I didn't know?
女呀！爱情是不可以当面包吃的
Daughter, love can't be like bread
找男朋友最紧要是门当户对
it's important that his status is the same
有些男人对你好，疼你  是想吃软饭
some treat you good just so they can depend on you
是啦...上车吧
yes! Hop in the car.
美亚
Mia...
中了一千九百万六合彩，很威风吗？
So what if you win $19 million
谁中了六合彩？
who won the Mark six?
不告诉你
I'm not telling you
-喝多一杯...
one more
大哥...
bro~
-来...
coming~
私人请你的
cheers!
生啤
Beer~~
猪眼看人低
don't look down at other people
有朝一日我笑口枣发了财
one day if I have the money
看我配不配得上你女儿
you'll see if I can be a good match for your daughter
喝...
drink up...
你的女朋友中了六合彩？
Did your girlfriend win the Mark six?
妈妈美亚
It was her mother!
“妈妈美亚” 中了
Mama Mia, won it!
“妈妈美亚”没天理
Mama Mia, my goodness
大哥有世界
let's do something!
做她妈妈世界
Let's do something to her mom
do something to her mom
就是她
Right, it's her!
不行啊，回去吧，计划临时取消
Let's go back. Postpone the plan!
什么事？
What happened?
那小妹妹认得我的
This little kid remember me
对呀
yes!
开车过去抢两对丝袜
Drive by and steal the pantyhose
穿上它
put it on!
有脑
You're smart!
不行，这尺码不合我
No, this size doesn't fit me
这是二号，我要穿四号的
this is size two and I need size four
-叫你套在头上而已
put it on your head
-对啊
yes!
拜拜
Bye
欧洲尺码，二号我也合穿
This is a European size, size two will fit me
我这对不合
this doesn't fit me
她要走了
she wants to leave
上去
go!
这边
This way
车门锁住了
Lock the door
-救命呀...  -这边
help!
救命呀  救命呀
Help...
-救命呀...  -快点
Help... Hurry
救命呀
Help...
来弟，去日本的行李收抬好了吗？
Have you finished packing for your Japan trip?
不用收抬了，带多几个空皮箱
There's nothing to pack empty suitcases will do
再带多几张信用卡就行了
and also bring a couple of credit cards
这次去，想买什么就买什么
this time I can buy whatever I want
-不要弄得孤孤寒寒，小小气气的  -是啊
I don't have to be stingy or tightfisted
-爸爸，过来看这个新电视机，立体声的
this television has stereo
-有十九年历史的恒丰银行  -开大声点
hang fung bank is bankrupt after nineteen years
好像是我们存钱的那间“恒丰”
It's looks like our bank, hang fung
涉及款项达到三百亿港元
it is $300 billion in the red
今次恒丰银行倒闭
it is bankrupt because, since 1985
自从八五年以来
a couple of banks had financial difficulties
继多间银行出现财政问题以后的第九宗
this's the ninth bank to go bankrupt!
大哥大嫂  我有一个好消息，一个坏消息
I got good news and bad news
你们想先听哪一个？
which do you want to hear first?
你先说个好消息来听
Tell us the good news first
好消息就是我的脚没有生脚癌
the good new is that I don't have leg cancer
是医生证实的
the doctor said that
那坏消息呢？
what about the bad news?
坏消息就是你们的一千九百万，没有了
The bad news is that you lost $19 million
-大嫂...  -你不要吓我
- whats! - Sister-in-law!
大嫂，你不要那么伤心
Don't be depressed
得失都是天注定的，你说的
whether you lose or win, it's fate
钱财和生命都是一样
money and life are the same
你有就有，没有就没有，都是天意
if you have it, you got it, it's fate
你还说这种风凉话  你害死我们了
stop bullshitting you caused us all this trouble
大哥，我也是受害者  我现在失业了
I'm a loser too, I lost my job
你赔我一千九百万
give me back $19 million
赔钱
爸爸
daddy
-赔钱  -你赔我一千九百万  我和你拼命呀  打得厉害点，厉害过史泰龙呀
give me back $19 million. Give it back!
-捏死你...  -赔钱...
...
我不理那么多,你还我一千九百万
一千九百万你还给我啊！还给我！
...
-绑票？
Kidnapped?
-你个衰佬，我要和你拼命  你们不要打了
Don't fight!
-小妹给人捉了去，给人绑票  -赔钱
Our sister was kidnapped!
不是开玩笑
No more jokes. We're not playing games
老爸，救我呀
dad, help me!
虽然你不疼我
I know you don't like me
我会养你一辈子
I will support you for your whole life
你不要让我死掉
don't let me die
听到了？  我们要一千九百万赎金
did you hear? We want $19 million ransom
开玩笑，我们才住公共屋邨
you must be joking we're living in the estates!
你又说中了六合彩
You said you won't the Mark six?
没有了，你没看电视
We don't have it. Didn't you hear the news?
那间恒丰倒闭了
Hang fung went bankrupt,
是吗？
whats?
开电视
Turn on the TV
你骠叔装穷呀
uncle bill, don't pretend that you are poor!
不对，是真的穷呀
No, I'm really poor!
不要装傻，快点预备钱
No more games, get toe money ready
如果报警，我就杀了她
if you tell the police, I'm going to kill her
大哥，报警
brother, call the police!
不行，报警他们会撕票的
We can't call the police. They will kill hostage
关你什么事，走
anyway it's none of your business. Get lost
现在怎么办？
What are we going to do now?
有老鼠咬我，我很害怕
A mouse bit me, I'm scared!
看来这件事是越来越严重了
It's getting worse and worse
岂止是严重，简直是超严重
what do you mean worse, it's super bad
全靠阿祖哥你亲自策划
brother Joe, you're the one responsible
亲自处理，亲自行动
a one man show
其实我只想吓吓那个肥婆
in reality, I just wanted to scare the fat woman
怎么知道一时冲动，搞出那么大一件事
who would've thought that a one-time impulse would get us in a huge mess?
是啊，美国当年扔原子弹，也是一时冲动
Yeah! It was also out of impulse when America built the atomic bomb.
现在全世界都说他对，做得好
Now, the world praises them for doing the right thing and having it well done.
-不如放了她  -放了她？
Why don't we let her go?
真是人头猪脑
Let her go?
-神经病  -傻子
- You're crazy! - Ate too much pig
现在放人，也是绑票
if we let her go now, it's still a kidnapping
收了一千九百万才放人，也是绑票
we receive $19 million, it's still a kidnapping
当然是收了钱才放人，傻子
the money first before we let tier go, stupid
我不玩了
I'm out of it!
现在大家都洗湿了头
We're all a part of it!
你玩不玩都大罪
Whether you're in or out, it's still a bad situation
趁他们还没揭穿你
since they still haven't blown your cover
你去他们家做卧底
go to their house and spy
如果他们报警，你就回来告诉我们
if they call the police, let us know
我先去洗个头
I'm going to wash my hair
去，快去洗湿头吧
go, go wash your hair!
笑口枣，你知不知我的女儿给绑票
Smiley Joe, did you know someone kidnapping her?
你知不知道是谁干的？
Do your know who is involved?
我怎么会知道
How do I know?
太好了
Good!
都是你不好
You never were any good!
干嘛要存外币
Why do you have a foreign account?
这样两千万没有了  二千万呀
$20 million, gone just that!
现在能讲“假如”
We can pretend that if wasn't real
就“假如”我们没中过好了
we can pretend that we never won
什么是假如？根本我们是中了
why should we pretend? I won!
到底你“曾经”有过二千万
Yes, you had $20 million!
你看隔壁左右，没有人“曾经”有过
Look around you, no one else had it
现在不是埋怨没钱
it not the time to talk about money
现在应该说怎么救女儿
we should think about how to rescue our daughter
不就是钱，没钱怎么救？
without money, how are we going to rescue her?
我把机票退了
I cancelled my plane ticket
这个我由小到大存起来的红包，全在这儿  来弟
even my personal saving are here!
句多不够钱赎小妹
Is this enough money to get sis back?
傻女，你真是乖了
Crazy girl, you're wonderful
来弟，你真乖
you're really wonderful!
-不要打电话
Don't use the phone
-不打！不打！
I'm n 0 t! I 1 m n ot!
糟了...他们真的没有钱了
They really don't have money
他们被银行骗完所有的钱，现在打回原型
the bank's bankrupts, they don't have money
那我们不是白费心机  好多蚊子呀
that means we're wasted our time?
不如把那小女孩放了算
Why don't we just let her go!
算？我们冒那么大风险
What? That's quite a risk
究竟他们还会有多少钱？
who knows how much money they have left?
大概一万多吧
About $10000!
一万多？  简直是侮辱，不放
About $10000. Forget it! We won't let her go!
除非他肯侮辱我们几十次
Unless she let's us insult her as much as we want
你们这样不是在乞丐碗里拿饭吃
it's like taking rice from a beggar's bowl!
拿到饭，你也有份吃
If we get the rice then you have a part in it too
不要感情用事
forget about feelings
她姐姐是你的女朋友，我知道
her sister is your girlfriend, I know
但是我们是你的兄弟
but we are your brothers!
-是吗？
Really?
-是不是？
Are you or not?
当然是了
Of course!
向他们要五十万
Ask them for $500000!
我是骠叔，你知道倒闭就好了
I'm uncle bill, you're... Aware of the bankrupt
什么？五十万
what? $500000
我现在就五万都没有
I don't even have $50000
你不要杀我的女儿，我给...
don't kill my daughter, I'll...
我女儿现在怎么啦
How's my daughter?
她很平安，我放她下来看电视
She is safe, she's watching TV
还给她吃糖
eating candy too
我的糖又大又甜
sweet and plenty of it
我要见到我女儿才给钱，招弟...
I want to see her first before I give you money
妈咪，这儿有很多老鼠
mommy, there's lot of mice here
听到了吧？向高利贷借五十万
you heard her? Go borrow $500000!
明天下午，你把钱入在二寸厚的皮箱中
Tomorrow afternoon put the money in a briefcase
拿住无线电话
take with you a portable telephone
去九龙塘乘三点九那班头等火车
go to kowloon tong and take the 3:45 tram
你就会看到你的女儿
you'll see your daughter then
你去那边准备偷拍
I'll video tape them secretly
-坐  -会不会在火车里交钱
are we going to exchange the money in the train?
我找遍了都没有绑匪和招弟
I looked all over I still can't see the kidnapper
你们现在在哪儿？
where are you now?
我们的火车刚过了中文大学
Our tram just passed the Chinese school
前面有一条公路
there's a hiway ahead your daughter will be there
你的女儿会在那儿出现
when you see her throw the money out of the tram
看到你女儿，就把钱扔出火车
I see...
窗不能开的，怎么扔？
the windows can't be opened, how do we throw it out?
去洗手间，那儿有窗可以扔钱出来
Go to the bathroom, use that window
就是这个窗啦
it's this window!
二寸厚的皮箱刚刚好
It's two inches thick, perfect
这列火车要到大埔墟才停站
this train stops at tai poi
即使我们报警
even if we call the police they have plenty of time
绑匪都有时间走
I can't even rescue my daughter
我见到女儿也不能救？
they're cunning!
真是狡猾  我出去拍他们的样子做证据
I'm going to shoot it for evidence
-爸爸...
dad!
-招弟...
Jody!
大哥，把钱扔出去
Big brother, throw the money out
-扔钱？
throw the money?
-爸爸
Dad!
-扔吧  -扔！
Throw the money!
爸爸
Dad!
快点扔吧
Throw the money!
招弟，快点回来
Jody, come quickly!
爸爸
Dad!
-大哥
Big brother!
-我没有钱了
I have no more money
你们收到钱，你们高兴了
I'm happy if you got the money!
骠叔，我真对不起你
Uncle bill, I'm sorry!
我会放你的女儿
I'll return your daughter
你是谁？
who are you?
糟了...
Oh! Shit!
你们在大埔墟下火车
You get off at tai poi
去马鞍山石矿场救你的女儿
go to the quarry, your daughter will be there
马鞍山石矿场？
the quarry...?
-钱啊！
Money...
-那个后轮掉了下去  推上来才行，来帮忙推一推车
The rear wheel's gone, help push the car
小妹，听住  待会我推你一下
Listen kid, I'm going to push you later
你说尿尿，我给机会让你开溜  知道吗？
you say piss & I'll give you a chance to leave
我知道了，笑口枣
I understand, smiley Joe
不过没有揭穿你
I knew it a long time ago, I just didn't say anything 1639?
怕你杀我灭口
I was afraid you would kill me
我很急，要去厕所
I need to go to the bathroom
不许吵
shut up!
-我忍不住了  -不准去
I can't hold it
-你要忍！忍！忍！
you can't go! You have to hold it!
-我忍不住了
I can't hold it
让她去吧，不然弄脏你的车就不好了
otherwise, she'll go inside the car
真麻烦  门也不关
she doesn't even close the door!
快点走
Run!
快点走！走...  有那远走那么远，走
Run, as far as you can!
你干嘛放了她？你发神经  不要，她是个小孩子
Why did you let tier go? Are you crazy?
不要杀她，她是个小孩子
we don't need to kill her she only a little girl
还想走
Still running!
没道理的
Can't bel
我去打电话告诉肥婆
I'll call my wife and let her know
兄弟  电话报警
brother, call the police
我杀你
I'm going to kill you!
招弟
Jody!
救命啊  救命啊
Help me!
-爸爸，救我呀
Daddy, help me!
-招弟...
Jody!
爸爸，救命啊
Daddy, help me!
-细叔...
Uncle!
-招弟...
Jody!
细叔
Uncle!
招弟
Jody!
大哥
Brother!
-爸爸...
Daddy!
-招弟...  -爸爸
- Jody! - Daddy,
不要离开我  -招弟...
- don't leave me! - Jody!
-女儿，爸爸疼你
One behind the rocks, another at the entrance
-爸爸，小妹
daughter, I love you!
家姐
Sis!
招弟
Jody!
妈妈
Mum!
-乖女儿，想死妈了，你没事吧  -妈妈
Good girl, you worried me to deal are you okay?
-你真是人渣，我打死你  -打死你...衰人
you drag, I'm going to beat you to death!
这儿还有一个
There's another one here
不关他的事，他来救我的
no, he's here to rescue me
他是好人，那两个才是绑匪
he's good, the other two are the kidnappers
-笑口枣，我爱你
smiley Joe, I love youl!
-笑口枣
Smiley Joe
他有份的...不要放了他
he's part of it, don't let him go!
不要放了他  笑口枣，你真是好人，我误会你了
Smiley Joe, you are good, I don't blame you
你是我心目中的大英雄
you're a hero in my eyes
你真是太好了，太好了
you're really good, really good!
他有份的，他也要抓去
He's involved, arrest him too!
生日快乐  生日快乐
Happy birthday to you~
好极了
yeah!
笑口枣，洗米呀
Smiley Joe, washing the rice?
煮饭呀
Cooking!
绑票那件事，只有你知道  不要告诉别人
You're the only one who know, don't tell anyone
以后我再也不会做坏人了
I'll never do anything bad again
招弟
Jody
笑口枣，姐姐找你
smiley Joe, sis is looking for you
-美亚，我来了
may, I'm coming!
-笑口枣
Smiley Joe!
一人一次，不拖不欠
We don't owe each other anything
还不快去洗脸
go wash your face!
想来我们都不是能做有钱人的
I don't want to be rich, risk being kidnapped
我有三个女儿已经是宝了
I have three daughters, that's precious
不止三个
not only three
-什么？你...
whats? You...
-大哥，恭喜你！
Brother, congratulations!
这次一定是个儿子
This time, it's got to be a boy
如果再生女儿
and if it's a another girl...
你会向医院退货
Give it back to the hospital!
对
Yes~yes~
现在有一项特别报告
now, there is special news
财政司刚在一个钟头前正式宣布
one hour ago, finance secretary officially announce
-动用外汇基金挽救恒丰银行  -谢谢...
hang fung bank was bailed out by foreign currency
虽然有多位大议员大力反对
even though many councilman are arguing against it
但是恒丰银行已经得到政府接管
hang fung has got the government s permission
决定明天复业
to reopen tomorrow
所有的存尸可以在银行提取他们的存款
whoever has an account may get their money back
发达咯
We're rich
-好棒啊...  -发达咯
We're rich again!
-是呀  -冷静！冷静！
Calm down! Calm down!
不要那么大声
Not so loud
不然让他们听到又要来借钱
don't let anyone know, they'll want to borrow money
老冯，我们没有钱再给你了
Mr. fung, I don't have any money to lend you
不是，我是来还所有借的钱
I'm here to return all the money I borrowed from you
我老婆和一个男人回家了
my wife came back with another man
他们一起回来住呀
they came back and we're living together!
你老婆有了男人你还那么开心？
Your wife is with another man and you're so happy
当然开心了  那个男人很有钱的
of course I'm happy, he's rich!
-老冯
Mr. fung
-有什么好事？
what?
贱格，你还是男人
You bastard, you're not a man!